aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Inside the hanger of Dag Base, there is a maintenance device for the machines.
다그 베이스의 격납고는 머신을 위한 관리(maintenance) 장치
Also, in this room, we can watch the image of our activities in a battle.
그리고, 이 방에서는 전투시의 우리들의 행동을 이렇게 영상으로 추척할 수 있어
But Dag Base isn't fully functional yet.
하지만, 활동중인 시스템은 다그 베이스의 일부에 지나지 않습니다
We do not know anything about the inactive functionality.
현재 잠들어 있는 장치의 기능은 일체 불명입니다
-Is it defunct?
-No way!
-불량품인가?
-설마
-Please come back, Ryu.
-OK.
-귀환해줘, 류
-OK
It's probably that something important is required to active Dag Base.
아마도, 다그 베이스를 발동시키기 위한 뭔가 중요한 요소가 걸려 있는 거겠지
Something important...
중요한 요소가...
Flashing Dag Base
섬광의 다그 베이스
Space Ant Zargoss Seijin
Appears
우주 개미 자고스 성인 등장
En!
엔~!
Where did you go to?
어디 갔었어?!
What's up, occult girl?
왜그래, 오컬트(occult) 소녀?
Gaku... Gaku's in trouble!
가쿠가... 가쿠가 큰일이야!
Gaku?
가쿠가?!
I wonder if En will come.
올까, 엔 녀석?
He'll come. We have a hostage.
올거다, 이쪽엔 인질이 있으니까 말야
How cowardly are you to take a feeble elementary school student as a hostage.
비겁해, 갸냘픈 초등학생을 인질로 삼다니 말야
Would a feeble elementary school student ask us for a hamburger?
갸냘픈 초딩이 햄버거 사달래냐?
Gimme another can!
주스 한병 더요
-Don't try to use us!
-Cheapskate.
-까불지마!
-쫌생이
Who are you?!
뭐냐, 네놈은?!
Hey, move! You're blocking the way!
야! 비켜, 못 지나가겠잖아
Don't you hear me? Move!
귀 먹었냐?! 비키라구!
It's been a long time.
오랜만이군
I hope you didn't forget about me.
잊어버렸다곤 못하겠지
A senior in Fuun High School who will make a crying baby shut up.
우는 애도 그친다는 풍운 고등학교 3학년
Geki Kuroiwa!
쿠로이와 게키!
Geki Kuroiwa.
Do you know him?
아는 사이냐?
I broke his arm and I was grounded for a week.
내가 저녀석의 팔을 부러뜨려서 일주일간 자택 근신을 먹었었어
I am Kai Hirose, a junior at Sankai High School.
산카이 고등학교 2학년 히로세 카이다
Excuse me, but did you see a elementary school student named Manabu Tobe?
무례를 용서하고 묻겠는데, 토베 마나부라고 하는 초등학생을 본 적이 있나?
Did... Did you take Gaku?!
설마, 설마 네놈이 가쿠를?!
-Answer me!
-That's right.
-대답해라!
-그렇다
If that's my answer, what'll you do?
라고 하면 어쩔텐가?
What?!
뭐야?!
I just wanted to pay you back for this arm.
너에게 이 팔의 빚을 갚고 싶어서 말야
-You bastard!
-En!
-이자식!
-엔!
Don't stop me! I cannot forgive such coward who takes a small kid as a hostage!
막지마! 꼬마애를 인질로 붙잡는 이런 비겁한 녀석만은 절대 용서 못해!
I was just going to say hi,
오늘은 인사만 하고 가려던 참이었지만
But you're not going back alive!
살아서 돌아갈 거라고 생각하지 마라!
That's for me to say!
그건 내가 할 소리다!
Wait!
기다려!
Just a moment before you fight!
그 싸움, 잠깐 기다려!
Gaku? What are you doing?
가쿠? 너, 대체...
Gaku!
가쿠!
Maria! This brother saved me!
누나! 이 형이 날 구해줬어
What?!
뭐라고?!
Are you serious, Gaku?
정말입니까, 가쿠 군?
If you think I'm lying, then why not take a look at there?
거짓말이라고 생각하면 저길 한번 보라구
Geki, you...
게키, 너...
The duel will be postponed.
결투는 보류다
But, En, I'll let you know this.
하지만, 엔
이것 만큼은 말해 두지
I will be the one who'll take care of you.
널 쓰러뜨리는건 바로 이몸이다
Then.
그럼...
Thank you for saving my brother.
저기, 동생을 구해주셔서 감사드립니다
Maria Tobe, a freshman at Sankai High School.
산카이 고등학교 1학년인 토베 마리아입니다
The president of Supernatural Phenomenon Research Club?
초상현상(超常現象) 연구회 회장?
Right! When you're troubled by some mysterious phenomenon, call me!
네! 괴기 현상 때문에 곤란하실 때에는 불러주세요
Uh...
저기...
Uh, excuse me.
아, 아, 이런.. 그럼, 실례
What the-?!
아니?!
Lian Vulcan!
라이안 발칸!
What is this?
뭐지, 이건?
Good morning, my cute cactus.
안녕, 텐 쨩
(역주 : サボテン -선인장)
You seem to be healthy today too!
오늘도 건강하구나
Am I pretty?
나 이뻐?
Mr. Kuroiwa!
쿠로이와 씨!
H- hello...
아, 안녕하십니까?
Well, don't just stay there and come in!
그런 곳에 있지 말고 안으로 들어오세요
I'm now testing Backster's effect.
지금 바쿠스타 효과 실험중이예요
Back... what?
바쿠... 뭐요?
I am trying to have a conversation with a cactus using a lie detector.
거짓말 탐지기를 써서 선인장과 대화하는 거예요
Talking with a cactus?
선인장과 대화...입니까?
I cheer for you!
응원할게요
I guess you came to have a match against En.
엔과 결투하러 온거죠?
Well, that's right.
뭐, 그런거죠
If he's not in the classroom, check out the mountain in the back. En skips class pretty often.
교실에 없다면 뒷산을 찾아보세요 엔 녀석, 가끔 땡땡이 치니까요
Ms. Maria!
마리아 씨!
Yes!
네!
I... I...
저, 저.. 저...
I have something that I want to give you!
어떻게든 당신에게 드리고 싶은게 있어서 그...
Spiritual pictures!
심령사진입니닷!
Spiritual pictures?
심령사진?
That's right! I got them from my album in the home!
그렇답니다! 집에 있는 앨범에서 싸그리 모아왔습니다만...
A stain in a wall.
벽의 얼룩
Double exposure, dust on the lens, and development miss.
이중 노출, 렌즈에 붙은 먼지, 현상 미스
It's a dust!
먼지가 찍힌 거구나
Sorry, too bad.
자, 유감이네요
Too bad?
유감?
A spiritual picture cannot be taken so easily!
심령사진이라는건 그렇게 간단히 찍히는게 아니예요
Oh, is that so?
그, 그렇군요
Wait!
기다려요!
Yes!
네!
You forgot these.
이거 챙겨 가셔야죠
S- sorry!
시, 실례했습니다!
What a weird guy.
이상한 사람이네
En?!
엔?!
Is this a clipper of a crab?!
이게 게의 집게발이라고?!
How many people can we feed with this?!
몇인분이냐, 이거?
Awesome! What an extraordinary crab's scissor!
대단해! 정말 경이로운 집게발이군요
What can be the reason of this?
대체 뭐가 원인이 되서 이런 모습으로?
I don't know. But I am sure that something frightening is happening under the sea.
모르겠어 하지만 바닷속에서 뭔가 무서운 일이 일어나고 있는건 틀림없어
It's inevitable. Let's skip the school and go find out.
할 수 없지, 학교 빠지고 조사하러 가자
Really, a friend of justice is tiring.
피차, 정의의 편은 고달프구만
Silence!
조용히 해!
Someone is coming.
누군가가 온다
It's cold here.
춥구만~
What the heck is En doing in this place?
이런 곳에서 무슨 짓을 벌이는거냐, 엔 녀석
Th- this is...
이, 이건?
-Geki?!
-En?!
-게키?!
-엔?!
Why the heck are you here?
너, 어째서 이런 곳에?!
No, why the heck are you here?!
너야말로 어째서 이런 곳에?!
En! You let him follow you!
엔! 너, 미행당했구나!
He saw Dag Base.
녀석은 다그 베이스를 봐 버렸다구
It's too dangerous to let him go back.
이대로 돌려보내는건 위험합니다
Let me down! What are you going to do with me?!
내려줘! 날 어쩔 셈이냐?!
You're noisy! I'll crush you if you don't shut up!
아아! 시끄럽구만! 시끄럽게 굴면 눌러 버린다!
En! Put him inside Dag Base.
엔! 녀석을 다그 베이스에 가둬라
Inside Dag Base?
다그 베이스에?
I'm sorry, but we'll have to imprison him until we solve the situation.
안됐지만, 사건을 해결할 때 까지 감금한다
We'll think about the dealing measure later.
녀석의 처분은 그 뒤에 생각하겠다
Hey, just a moment! What do you mean by measure?!
잠깐 기다려! 처분이라니?!
Hey, let me out! What the heck are you thinking?!
이봐! 내보내줘! 무슨 생각을 하고 있는 거냐, 네놈들?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Will it be alright to let Geki inside?
게키 녀석을 두고 와도 괜찮을까?
This is no time to worry about that.
지금은 그럴 때가 아니잖아
Investigation comes first.
바닷속을 조사하는게 조사가 급선무다
That's right, but...
그건 그렇지만 말야
Did something happen to Yoku?
요쿠에게 무슨 일이 있는 건가?
Yoku!
요쿠!
I'm alright!
괘, 괜찮습니다!
You're not running away!
놓칠 것 같냐?!
You bastard!
요놈!
What is this?!
여기는?
I'm sorry, but we'll have to imprison him until we solve the situation.
안됐지만, 사건을 해결할 때 까지 감금한다
We'll think about the dealing measure later.
녀석의 처분은 그 뒤에 생각하겠다
The oxygen isn't enough.
산소가 매우 희박해
Poisonous gas is filling the atmosphere.
대기에는 유독 가스가 가득 차 있어
Temperature, humidity, and air pressure are different from our world.
기온, 습도, 기압 모두 우리들의 세계와 다릅니다
I guess this strange environment resulted in giant crabs and octopuses.
아마도 이 이상한 환경이 거대한 게와 문어를 탄생시킨 거겠죠
I remembered.
생각났다
What's wrong, Lian?
왜그래, 라이안?
Zargoss castle.
자고스 성이다
Zargoss castle?
자고스 성?
That ant-like alien?
그 개미같이 생긴 우주인 말야?
Right. This space is just like Zargoss castle.
그래, 이 공간은 자고스 성과 꼭 닮은 환경이야
Don't say stupid! This is deep in the ocean, of the Earth!
바보같은 소리마! 여기는 지구의, 그것도 깊은 바닷속이라구
No. What Lian is saying is right.
아니, 아마 라이안의 말대로인 것 같다
How do you know about that?!
어떻게 그런걸 알 수 있냐?
Zargoss Seijin?!
자고스 성인?!
I see. They succeeded in making the environment of Zargoss castle artificially!
그렇군, 녀석들은 인공적으로 자고스 성의 환경을 만들어내는데 성공한 거야!
I guess they're planning to move underground, but no way!
땅속으로 이주할 속셈인 것 같지만 그렇게 내버려 둘 것 같냐!
Lio Sword!
라이오 소드!
Blizzard Hurricane!
블리자드 허리케인!
Breast Motor Cannon!
브레스트 모터 캐논!
Big Spiral Whirlwind Slash!
대회전 검풍참!
Wheel Kick!
호일 킥!
On your back!
뒤쪽이다!
Geki, was that you?!
게키! 지금 그 목소리, 너냐?!
En?
엔?
You idiot! Don't bum around inside Dag Base!
바보자식! 멋대로 다그 베이스 안을 싸돌아다니지 마라!
Shut up! What the heck are you!
닥쳐! 네놈은 대체 정체가 뭐냐?!
I have no time to talk with you! Get back to Dag Base...
지금 너와 이야기할 시간 없어! 얌전히 다그 베이스로...
That guy again?!
또 이녀석이냐!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!
En...
엔...
Star Burn!
스타 번!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
Shoot!
슛!
You idiot!
바보녀석!
This underground Zargoss space is just in an experimental stage!
이 지하 자고스 공간은 그저 실험단계일 뿐이다
What do you mean?
무슨 소리지?!
Look at this!
이걸 봐라!
Zargoss Light Wave Missile!
자고스 광파(光波) 미사일
With this one, one thirds of the Earth becomes Zargoss castle!
이 한발로 지구의 약 1/3은 순식간에 자고스 성으로 변한다!
What?!
뭐야?!
H- hey!
이, 이봐!
No way!
놓칠 것 같냐!
You're too late!
이미 늦었어!
You're too late, Dagwons!
늦었단 말이다, 다그온!
Then!
좋아!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Alright.
좋아!
En!
엔!
Wake up, En! Open your eyes!
일어나, 엔! 눈을 떠라!
You bastard! Are you going to be defeated in a place like that?!
이자식! 그런 곳에서 나자빠질 셈이냐?!
Are you scared of fighting against me, you idiot?!
나와의 승부가 무서운 거냐, 바보자식아!
You call yourself a man?!
그러고도 남자냐?!
If you're mortified, stand up!
분하면 일어나란 말이다!
Stand up and show your guts, En!
일어나서 근성을 보여라, 엔!
Can't I do something?!
어떻게 안되는 거냐?!
No good!
틀렸어!
Please, En! Wake up!
부탁이다, 엔! 눈을 뜨라구!
I am the one who'll take you down!
널 쓰러뜨리는건 바로 이몸이다!
Don't die! You can't die!
죽지 마라! 죽어선 안돼!
If you die, I cannot forgive!
죽으면 내가 용서 못해!
Do you hear me, En?!
들리냐, 엔?!
En!
엔!
What's that light?!
저 빛은?!
Dag Base has left us a big mystery.
다그 베이스는 우리에게 커다란 수수께끼를 남기고
And it fall asleep again.
다시 잠들어 버린 건가
Geki!
게키!
I have nothing to do with the fact that you guys are Dagwons or not.
너희들이 다그온이든 뭐든 나와는 관계 없다
Then I'll assume that you won't expose our secret.
그럼 우리들의 비밀은 발설하지 않겠지?
I keep promises.
난 약속은 지킨다
But, En, I'll tell you once again.
하지만, 엔
다시 한번 말해두지
I am the one who'll take you down.
너를 쓰러뜨리는건 바로 이몸이다
Don't lose to weaklings like Sargasso's aliens.
사르갓소의 우주인 녀석 따위에게 지지 말라구
That punk!
저녀석!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Everyone, have you ever wanted to become strong to defeat anyone who bullies you?
다들! 너희들은 강해져서 자신을 괴롭히는 아이에게 이기고 싶다고 생각한 적 없니?
Gaku's classmate Tsuyoshi picked up a suspiciously shining rock.
가쿠의 학급 친구 쯔요시가 수상하게 빛나는 돌을 주웠어
From that day, he got a weird superpower.
그 날부터 이상한 초능력을 얻게 되어 버렸어
But that is actually Phoenix Seijin's fearful trap!
하지만 그녀석은 말야! 피닉스 성인의 무서운 함정이라구!
Don't fall over to the power of death, Tsuyoshi!
죽음의 힘에 넘어가지 마라, 쯔요시!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Cowardly Tsuyoshi and Space Rock
다음회 용자지령 다그온
겁쟁이 쯔요시와 우주석
Dagwon's with you!
다그온이 함께 있다구!
Cowardly Tsuyoshi and Space Rock
겁쟁이 쯔요시와 우주석